Roger Waters: The Wall is a music, documentary film directed by Roger Waters.
A concert film that the former Pink Floyd singer-songwriter made on various tour dates between 2010
and 2013, when he was playing his former group's 1980 double-album in its entirety.
Self - Vocal, Guitar, and Bass, played by Roger Waters.
Self - Guitars, played by Dave Kilminster.
Self - Drums, played by Graham Broad.
Self - Guitars, played by Snowy White.
Self - Keyboards, played by Jon Carin.
Roger Waters: The Wall is a British concert film by Roger Waters.
Directed by Waters and Sean Evans, it captures
performances of Waters' live tour.
It premiered in the Special Presentations section of the 2014 Toronto
International Film Festival, with Waters and Evans in attendance.
The concert design and execution draws heavily from the original concert of the same
name that followed the release of the Pink Floyd album The Wall (1979).
In addition to the 90 minutes of music, the film also contains interspersed documentary and
interview footage taken from a road trip in Europe, with Waters driving an old Bentley.
Waters is also seen reading from John Berger's introduction to Fear, the
English translation of Gabriel Chevallier's novel, La Peur.
The audio is presented in 7.1.4-channel Dolby Atmos.
The film explores themes of concert, live performance, concert film.